Privacy Policy
--------------

This Privacy Policy explains what information OpenNIC.org and its related entities collect about its users, what we do with that information and how we handle the content you place in our products and services.

Scope of Privacy Policy
-----------------------

This Privacy Policy applies to the information that we obtain through your use of OpenNIC.org services via a Device or when you otherwise interact with OpenNIC’s official web services.

OpenNIC.org services include our:

* Websites (opennic.org and subdomains \*.opennic.org),

but does not include:

* Products or services for which a separate privacy policy is provided.
* Third Party Products. These are third party products or services that you may discover on our website or other official services, such as OpenNIC DNS servers listed on the official Servers page. You should always review the policies of third party products and services to make sure you are comfortable with the ways in which they collect and use your information.

Website Visitors
----------------

Like most website operators, OpenNIC.org collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. OpenNIC.org’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how OpenNIC.org’s visitors use its website and related services. From time to time, OpenNIC.org may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

OpenNIC.org also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. OpenNIC.org does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

Opting-out of Website Tracking
------------------------------

Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information
-----------------------------------------------

Certain visitors to OpenNIC.org’s websites choose to interact with OpenNIC.org in ways that require OpenNIC.org to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that OpenNIC.org gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who use our [membership services](https://members.opennicproject.org/) to provide a username and email address. In each case, OpenNIC.org collects such information only as in necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with OpenNIC.org. OpenNIC.org does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information
--------------------------------------------------------

OpenNIC.org will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

If you are a registered user of an OpenNIC.org mailing list, OpenNIC.org may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with OpenNIC.org and our organization. We expect to keep this type of email to a minimum.

OpenNIC.org takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Aggregated Statistics
---------------------

OpenNIC.org may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites, and may reveal generalized statistics related to a variety of our services.

We are currently releasing non-personally-identifying information to the public at [https://matomo.opennic.org/](https://matomo.opennic.org/).

Cookies
-------

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. OpenNIC.org uses cookies to help OpenNIC.org identify and track visitors, their usage of OpenNIC.org website, and their website access preferences. OpenNIC.org visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using OpenNIC.org’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of OpenNIC.org’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

Privacy Policy Changes
----------------------

Although most changes are likely to be minor, OpenNIC.org may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in OpenNIC.org’s sole discretion. OpenNIC.org encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Contact Us
----------

OpenNIC is a community run effort. Official queries should be addressed to the `discuss` Mailing List, as detailed [on the Wiki](https://wiki.opennic.org/opennic/mailinglist). Informal queries can also be sent to our [IRC](https://www.opennic.org/contact/) channel.

For comments, questions, or issues with this site specifically, or this privacy policy, please [open an issue](https://github.com/opennic/opennic-web/issues) on GitHub.
